ERIC KIM

North Wales, PA

Phone: (703) 371-7367 | Email: erickimek86@gmail.com LinkedIn: /eric-kim-221a437b | GitHub: /EricKim86 | Portfolio: EricKim86.github.io/react-portfolio

SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer, experienced leader with 14 years of retail and project management experience. Inspiring leader that is consistent in delivering positive results through performance management and collaboration. Strong attention to detail, strategic planning, and problem solving. Numerous sales and leadership accolades.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript ES6+, CSS3, HTML5, SQL, NoSQL, GitHub, MongoDB, MySQL, Express, React, Node, Handlebars, jQuery, Bootstrap

WORK EXPERIENCE

District Manager Guitar Center

2018 - 2022 Westlake Village, CA

Responsible for numerous locations across three states focusing on positive EBIDTA contribution. Accountable for the growth and development of a team of nearly 300 associates and managers. Managed labor, store standards, strategic company initiatives, and customer satisfaction.

Manager of Sales Administration and Retail Support Guitar Center

2017 -2018 Westlake Village, CA

Worked with business partners to create initiatives to drive incremental sales across the entire retail organization. Led weekly calls with the District Management team to disseminate information and key initiatives.

Operations / General Manager Guitar Center

2011 -2017 Various Locations

Led teams in achieving positive sales growth and maintaining Customer Satisfaction scores above company average. Developed a strong manager bench through consistent performance management and setting expectations.

PROJECTS

Dare-Devil-Deals | /EricKim86/dare-devil-deals | /lit-dusk-01074.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: Ecommerce MERN stack application developed in one week.
- Role: Project Lead
- Tools: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Node.js, Express.js, React, Bootstrap

Disney Character Loctor | /EricKim86/disney-character-locator | /https://erickim86.github.io/disney-character-locator/

- Summary: Application utilizing two APIs to populate Disney character appearances in films.
- Role: Project Lead
- Tools: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Bulma,

EDUCATION

Full Stack Certificate - University of Pennsylvania

Philadelphia, PA

A 12-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, and ReactJS.

Bachelors of Science, Electronic Engineering - ECPI University

Glen Allen, VA

Bachelors of Arts, Music Industry- Randolph-Macon College

Ashland, VA